Guide to the Northern Virginia Oral History Project collection, 1958-1996
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Northern Virginia Oral History Project collection
1958-1996
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Northern Virginia Oral History Project
C0030
2.5 linear feet
The collection contains 96 taped interviews of Northern Virginia residents. Transcripts or abstracts accompany most of the recordings. Topics such as agriculture, development, education, health, politics, transportation, and religion, with respect to Northern Virginia in the 19th and 20th centuries, are discussed.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research although some interviews may have restrictions.
Custodial History
The collection was previously housed in the Fairfax County Library from 1962-1983. It was transferred to George Mason University Libraries in 1984.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by the Fairfax City Regional Library in 1992. Additional interviews added in 1996.
Historical Information
The Northern Virginia Oral History Project Collection is comprised of interviews conducted between 1962 and 1983. The interviews document community and family life, and careers in the Northern Virginia Area as well as changes in Northern Virginia since World War II.
Scope and Content
The collection contains 96 taped interviews of Northern Virginia residents. Transcripts or abstracts accompany most of the recordings. Topics such as agriculture, development, education, health, politics, transportation, and religion, with respect to Northern Virginia in the 19th and 20th centuries, are discussed.
The eighty interviews in Series 1, taped between 1958 and 1983, document community and family life, careers, etc. in the Northern Virginia Area. The sixteen interviews in Series 2, conducted in 1982-1983, deal primarily with changes in Northern Virginia since World War II. The transcripts are in Series 3. Series 4 contains the Northern Virginia Leadership Project interviews. Roy Rosenzweig, a professor in Mason's History Department, supervised the final phase of the project. The Northern Virginia Leadership Project is a collection of interviews with prominent figures from the Northern Virginia area. The collection includes 9 interviews conducted between the years 1990 and 1996.
Arrangement
Organized into four series.
Series 1: Northern Virginia Community, 1958-1983
Series 2: Northern Virginia Changes, 1982-1986
Series 3: Transcripts, 1962-1983
Series 4: Northern Virginia Leadership Project, 1990-1996
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds many other oral histories about Northern Virginia, particularly Reston, Virginia.
Index Terms
Geographical Names:
Virginia, Northern--History.
Contents List
- Series 1: Northern Virginia Community, 1958-1983
  - ADAMS, IDA. Reminiscences of two former students at Forestville School, Great Falls, VA December 21,1969, 1 sound cassette (45 min) mono.; 1 abstract (1p) (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - ALDEN ROBERT M. Life in Lewinsville, Langley, and McLean, VA(ca 1800-1960) with particular focus on Lewinsville Presbyterian Church September 23,1973, 1 sound cassette (37 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - BAILEY, CHARLES. The Navy School and other schools in Pender,VA May 6,1970, 1 sound Cassette (11 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel(master); 1 abstract (1p) (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - BATES, MILDRED. Life in the Community (1917-1945). February 9, 1983, 1 sound cassette (45 min) mono.; 1 abstract (1p) (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - BEARD JOSEPH. Agricultural practices and farm life in Fairfax County, VA. November 21, 1974, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel(master); 21 page transcript (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - BEARD, JOSEPH. Fairfax County Library National Book Week. April 19, 1974., 1 sound cassettes (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - BEARD, JOSEPH. Community and family life in Floris and Herndon, VA January 23,1979, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 25 page transcript (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - BEARD, JOSEPH. Dairy farming in Fairfax County, VA in the 1930s with emphasis on the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1933 March 6, 1979, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 25 page transcript (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - BEARD, JOSEPH. Reminiscences of Fairfax County, Va Agricultural Agent August 9, 1975, 2 sound cassette (120 min) mono.; 1 abstract (4p) (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - BENNETT, MABEL. Community Life at Fairfax Court House (c.1900-80) with Elsie Lucas. December 6,1982, 1 sound cassette; 1 abstract (1p) (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - BESLEY, OLIVER W., Jr. Wakefield Chapel, Fairfax County, VA November 10, 1976, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 11 page transcript(missing 10/92) abstract (4p) (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - BIRCH, ALVIN ASHTON. Schools and transportation in Fairfax County, VA. A, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel(master).; 1 abstract(2p.) (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - BIRCH, ALVIN ASHTON. Work and religion in Pender, VA January 6, 1977, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 12 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - BLACK, ELIZABETH. Community life in Dunn-Loring, VA June 21, 1971, 2 sound cassette (90 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel(master).; 1 abstract (2p). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - BLAKE, RONALD. Schools, farming, and transportation in Oakton, VA December 21, 1969, 1 sound cassette (25 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel(master).; 1 abstract (1p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - BLES, MARCUS J.July 22, 1975., 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - BOSTON, MERVIN. Family life in McLean, Va March 8,1973, 2 sound cassette (90 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel(master).; 1 abstract (2p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - BOWMAN, LEONARD WILBUR. Oakton History including Church of the Brethren, electric railway, dairies, Hell's Hole, FFA, 4-H, Electric Railway in Oakton. September 17,1981, 1 sound cassette. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - BRECKENRIDGE, ALMA WILLIAMS. School in Herndon, VA, 1 sound cassette (35 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master).; 1 abstract (1p) (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - BROWN, EARL 1970 (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - BRUMSTED, MARGARETH R.August 23, 1984., 3 sound cassettes (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - BUCKMAN, BERTHA. Woodlawn School, Fairfax County, VA April 28, 1970, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master)., 1 abstract (2p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - BUCKMAN, CHRISTINE April 28,1970 (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - BUCKMAN, HORACE April 28,1970 (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - CANTERBURY, TED. Burke Center. August 22, 1985, 1 sound cassette. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - CARTER, RENA. Schools in Fairfax County, VA February 20, 1970, 1 sound cassette (18 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master).; 12 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - CECCHI, GIUSEPPE. Burke Center Development. August 27, 1985., 1 sound cassette; 15 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - CHASE, SANDRA. Wakefield Chapel, Fairfax County, VA and its environs December 8,1976, 1 sound cassette (30 min) mono.; 8 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - CLEVELAND, JAMES. Reston. February 4, 1982, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - COBB, NORMAN. Oakton History including Gray's florist business, Gray subdivision, van der Vies competition, Oakton School, Oaktan as a farming community, Fairfax Court House, and Vienna banking November 21, 1980, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - COCKRELL, ALFRED H. December 11. 1971, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - COOPER, MATTIE April 28, 1970, 1 sound cassette (18 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master).; 12 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - CORNER, CHARLOTTE. Community life in McLean, VA with emphasis on schools and transportation. August 12, 1971, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 1 sound reel (master).; 43 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - CROLL, DONALD L. Wakefield Chapel, Fairfax County, VA: legal aspects of its deed of trust February 20, 1970, 1 sound cassette (30 min) mono.; 3 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - CROSS, MARY KENYON. Oakton History, WWI, Kenyon Family, Arlington-Fairfax Electric Railroad, Church of the Brethren, Methodist Church, Whitesells, Cobbs, Bowmans, Millers October 28, 1980, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - DANISAVAGE, GLORIA. Preservation of Wakefield Chapel, Fairfax County, VA January 22, 1977, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 13 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - DANISAVAGE, VICTOR January 22, 1977, 1 sound cassette (18 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master).; 12 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - DOUGLAS, HENRY H. Early Roads in Northern Virginia; Part I August 1, 1974, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - DOWNEY, JERRY. September 29, 1975, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - DOWNS, JOE. Fairfax Then and Now Lecture. October 17, 1972, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - DUNN, PEARL Family life in Merrifield, VA August 20, 1971, 1 sound tape reel (master); 31 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - DWYER, HOBART March 8, 1973 (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - DWYER, HOBART. Community life in the McLean and Langley, VA area: with emphasis on the "Strawberry Vale" house February 12, 1973, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master).; 1 abstract(2p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - ELLIOT, JEAN. Fairfax Then and Now: a lecture titled "Potpourri of Alexandria" September 26, 1972, 1 sound tape reel (master); 1 abstract (1p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - ELLMORE, ELIZABETH. Community life in Floris, VA March 8, 1979, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 25 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - ELLMORE, EMMA March 8,1979 (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - ELLMORE, EMMA. Reminiscences of a Fairfax County VA. teacher with emphasis on her "Citizen of the Year" award. March 21, 1971, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master).; 1 abstract (2p) (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - FARRELL, ESTON C. December 9, 1982 (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - FERGUSON, LULAH B. Reminiscences of a school teacher in Falls Church, Floris, Herndon, and Vienna, Va August 16, 1971, 1 sound cassette (28 min) mono.; 1 sound reel tape(master).; 19 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - FIFER, CARSON LEE, JR. Family life at Mount Eagle, Fairfax County, VA July 1, 1981, 1 sound cassette (30 min) mono.; 1 abstract (2p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - FIFER, CARSON LEE SR. Community and family at Mt. Eagle, Fairfax County, VA (c.1941-62) April 4, 1981, Abstract (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - FLAKNE, JOSEPH. December 23, 1983, 2 sound cassettes (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - FORD, W. HAROLD. Reminiscences of former teachers in Fairfax County, VA. December 13, 1970, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master).; 1 abstract (2p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - FORSYTHE, EDWIN. December 8-9, 1982, 1 sound cassettes (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - GAMBLE, ROBERT S. Herndon Historical Meeting: Sully Plantation October 9, 1975, 1 sound cassette. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - GANTT, FLOYD March 8, 1973, 1 sound cassette (18 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master).; 12 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - GANTT, FLOYD February 12, 1973 (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - GANTT, JOHN February 12, 1973 (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - GARDNER, WILLIAM. Lecture on the History of Indians in NOVA. October 24, 1972, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HAIGHT, ALEX. May 5, 1971, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HAIGHT, ALEX. July 15, 1971, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HAIGHT, ALEX. September 13, 1971, 2 sound cassettes (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HAIGHT, ALEX. Visit to Little Sully. March 23, 1973, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HALL, NACY. Reminiscences of a teacher in Fairfax County VA, including a discussion of her father, Milton D. Hall, Superintendent of Schools for Fairfax County March 15, 1970, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master).; 24 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HARRISON, HOLDEN March 6, 1979 (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HARRISON, HOLDEN. Dairy farming in Herndon and Floris, VA February 5, 1979, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 22 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HARRISON, HOLDEN. Reminiscences of a dairy farmer in Herndon, VA March 4,1981, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 11 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HARRISON, LOUISE PRESGRAVE February 5, 1979, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 11 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HARRISON, LOUISE PRESGRAVE. Teaching in Fairfax County, VA May 14,1970, 1 sound cassette (58 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel(master); 24 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HARRISON, RAY February 5,1979 (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HATCH,DR. WINSLOW. McLean Historic Sites January 19,1975, 2 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HAWXHURST, RICHARD W. Oakton History, Squire Ernest Smith, Toll gates, Robert Burley, Chain Bridge Road, Hell's Hole, Difficult Run, Waple Farm, Electric Trolley Line, Brethren Church, Hawxhurst Family September 10, 1980, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HEALY, MICHAEL. August 20, 1981, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HENDERSON, EDWIN B. Black education in Fairfax County, VA public schools(1920-1950) with particular focus on the James Lee Elementary School June 13, 1969, 1 sound cassette (30 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master); 14 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HENDERSON, EDWIN B. Community life in the Falls Church and Tysons areas of Northern Virginia (ca. 1910-1960) with particular focus on black churches, schools, and organizations 1962, 2 sound cassette (120 min) mono.; 48 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HENDERSON, EDWIN B. Race relations, education, and social life in Northern Virginia and Washington, D.C. 1965, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 21 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HENDERSON, MARRY ELLEN June 13,1969 (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HINE, ETHEL LYNN June 21,1971 (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HIRST, EDNA B. Family and community life in Annandale, VA with particular focus on church attendance January 25,1977, 1 sound cassette (30 min) mono.; 9 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HOGE, DOROTHY December 13,1970 (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HOGE, DOROTHY May 14,1970, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 11 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HOGE, DOROTHY. Reminiscences of the principal of Hayfield Elementary School, Fairfax County June 8,1970, 1 sound cassette (30 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master).;1 abstract (2p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HOLLAND, WILL. Tomb Guard (George Washington's ) Speech December 1958, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 11 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HONESTY, COLUMBUS C. Life in the black community of Vienna, VA. September 11,1972, 1 sound cassette (45 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master).; 1 abstract (1p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HUGHES, ADRIAN April 28,1970 (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HUGHES, RALPH AND PAT. Oakton Trolley Station February 5, 1989, 1 sound cassette; 5 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - INGEBRETSIN, KARL. August 25, 1981, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - JACKSON, JOHN. with granddaughter Denise Johnson. February 2, 1988, 2 sound cassettes (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - JACKSON, SELENA. December 9, 1983, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - JONES, REV. ALBERT. Off the Record Club; the vestry in Va. history. September 14, 1974, 2 sound cassettes (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - JONES, REXTON. County doctors in Fairfax County, VA (ca. 1890 1930) with emphasis on Dr. James Tasker Jones and the Herndon area. February 7,1973, 2 sound cassettes (75 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel(master).; 1 abstract (2p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - KEITH, JAMES. Reminiscences of a member of the Fairfax County (VA) Board of Supervisors (ca. 1956-62) with particular emphasis on politics, transportation, and suburbanization March 11,1974, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel(master).; 16 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - KEPHART, HERMAN. Community life in Herndon, VA (ca.1920-1960) with particular focus on schools, employers, and suburbanization March 16,1973, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master).; 1 abstract (2p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - KIRBY, MARVIN. Community life in McLean, VA. (ca.1900-1970) January 24, 1971, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 7 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - LANDES, MELVIN December 13,1970, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 11 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - LANDES, MELVIN. Reminiscences of a school teacher in Fairfax County, VA-(ca. 1920-1945) June 24,1969, 1 sound cassette (55 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel(master).; 1 abstract (3p.). page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - LEIGH, HASSELL. County doctors in Great Falls, Herndon, Leesburg, and Dranesville, VA.(ca. 1880-1920) November 13, 1972, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel(master).; 1 abstract (1p.) (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - LEIGH, M.V. December 29, 1979, 1 sound cassette. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - LEIGH, W.LEWIS, Jr. Oakton History, Oakton Elementary School, Civil War in the Blake Lane Area July 9, 1980, 1 sound cassette. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - LEIGH, W. LEWIS, Sr. Oakton History July 9, 1980, 1 sound cassette. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - LITTLE, GRACE DOVE. June 24, 1983, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - LOTH, CALDER. Architectural discussion on historical sights in Fairfax County, VA-Huntley, Mt. Air, and Mt. Gilead May 12, 1969, 3 sound cassettes (180 min.) mono,; 1 abstract (1p.) (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - LUCAS, ELSIE December 6, 1982 (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - LUSBY, EDWARD AND JEAN. Oakton History July 21, 1981, 1 sound cassette. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - MACOMBER, WALTER. Dranesville Tavern, Dranesville, VA. (ca. 1968) 1968, 2 sound cassettes (120 min) mono.; 1 abstract (1p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - MADDOX, MAY. Life at Dranesville Tavern, Dranesville, VA. (ca. 1920-1965) with emphasis on tavern services, costs, and facilities February 26, 1968, 2 sound cassettes (50 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master).; 1 abstract (2p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - MARTIN, MABELLE June 21, 1971 (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - MERGLER, Mrs. Life as a member of Mormon (LDS) Church., 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - MEYER, JOHN J. June 21, 1971 (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - MIDDLETON, REBECCA March 8, 1979 (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - MILLARD, EMMA. Family life in Vienna and Herndon, VA. (ca. 1920 1935) with emphasis on Colvin Run Mill, schools, roads, and transportation November 15,1972, 2 sound cassettes (120 min) mono.; 2 sound tape reel(master).; 50 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - MILLARD, LOUISE November 15,1972, 2 sound cassettes (120 min) mono.; 1 abstract (1p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - MONEY, ELSIE. Family life in Vienna, VA. (ca.1900-1960) with particular focus on schools, transportation, and country doctors July 2, 1974, 1 sound cassette (30 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel, (master); 1 abstract (1p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - MURPHY, LOUISE December 13,1970, 2 sound cassettes (120 min) mono.; 1 abstract (1p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - OLSON, RUTH TAYLOR. Oakton History, Electric Trolley Line, Squire Smith Line, W.R. Gray Nursery, Oakton High, Social Events. September 19, 1980, 1 sound cassette. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - OSBORN, ILAH June 21,1971 (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - OSBORN, ILAH. Community life in Falls Church and Mclean, VA. (cs. 1930-1975) with emphasis on schools, civic affairs, and suburbanization April 28, 1975, 2 sound cassette (100 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master); 1 abstract (3p.) (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - PEARSON, SAMUEL. Family life in Lewinsville and Vienna, VA. (ca. 1900-1975) with emphasis on family land holdings by Samuel Pearson and Alfred P. Souder. October 26, 1978, 43 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - PECK, MARGARET C. Sully Planation October 10, 1979, 2 sound cassettes; 1 abstract (2p.); 35 page transcript (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - PETERS, VIRGINIA 1970 (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - POSTON, BERTIE. April 1980, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - PRICHARD, E.A. August 18, 1981, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - PULLEY, ANNE. Family life and schooling in Fairfax County VA(ca. 1895-1975) with emphasis on Wakefield Chapel November 11, 1976, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 11 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - ROBINSON, B. OSWALD. Reminiscences of a teacher in Fairfax County, VA. (ca. 1910-1970) June 23, 1970, 1 sound cassette (29 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master).; 1 abstract (2p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - ROBINSON, FREDERICK The Fairfax County(VA) School Board and school consolidation (ca. 1933-1953) April 12, 1970, 1 sound cassette (30 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master).; 1 abstract (1p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - ROBINSON, LILLIAN R. March 24, 1983 (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - ROGERS, EDITH. Reminiscences of a school teacher in Fairfax County VA. (ca. 1915-1960) with emphasis on Forestville, Herndon, and Fairfax high schools June 12, 1970, 1 sound tape reel (master).; 20 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - ROUNSEVELL, GLENN. Moving Flint Hill School February 3, 1989, 1 sound cassette (29 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master).; 1 abstract (2p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - SAUNDERS, GLENN. August 25, 1981, 1 sound cassette. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - SHERMAN, CAROLINE. Reminiscences of a student at the Freedom Hill School, Great Falls, VA. (ca. 1925-1940) with emphasis on one room schools, transportation, and school board membership April 13, 1970, 1 sound cassette (30 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master).; 1 abstract (2p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - SHREVE, EDGAR June 21, 1971 (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - SHREVE, EDGAR. Family life in Dunn-Loring, VA (ca. 1890-1945) with emphasis on transportation, the Great Depression, and the flood of 1936 July 31, 1972, 2 sound cassette (90 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master).; 1 abstract (2p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - SOUDER, ALFRED P. October 26,1978, 1 sound cassette (29 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master).; 1 abstract (2p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - SPAULDING, CATHERINE KLEBER. Oakton History, Henry Hawxhurst, electric railway, Hawxhurst Family August 22, 1980, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - SPEER, BERNARD A. Oakton History, William and Cornelius Speer, Pre-Civil War, Oakton High, Waples swimming hole, Dr. Edward Latch-Methodist Minister, House of Representatives, C.T. Rice, Jermantown, Church of the Brethren, Interurban, Hunter's Mill June 18, 1980, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - STUNZ, W. MAYO. Oakton History, Chain Bridge Road, Oakton Elemetary, Trolley Line, Auto Railer, Fairgrounds, Gray's Nursery, Stuntz Family June 11, 1980, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - SWINK, C.C. Community life in Great Falls, VA.(ca. 1915-1970) with emphasis on mill ownership, roads, and transportation August 23, 1971, 1 sound tape reel (master).; 32 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - VAN PATTEN, FRANCES. Family life in Great Falls, VA (ca. 1895-1930) with emphasis on Swinks Mill August 19, 1971, 1 sound tape reel (master).; 35 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - VOZZOLO, ELIZABETH MARY. Community life in Fairfax County, VA(ca. 1850-1975) with emphasis on Wakefield Chapel, Part 3 February 7, 1977, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 13 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - VOZZOLO, ELIZABETH MARY. Family life in Fairfax County, VA (ca. 1850-1970) with emphasis on Wakefield Chapel(1850-1972), Part 1 November 18, 1976, 1 sound cassette (20 min) mono.; 1 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - VOZZOLO, ELIZABETH MARY. Family life in Fairfax County, VA (ca. 1850-1975) with emphasis on Wakefield Chapel, Part 2 December 10, 1976, 1 sound cassette (30 min) mono.; 16 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)